Something wicked this way comes.
Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban is a adventure,
fantasy film directed by Alfonso Cuarón.
Year three at Hogwarts means new fun and challenges as Harry learns the delicate art of approaching a
Hippogriff, transforming shape-shifting Boggarts into hilarity and even turning back time.
But the term also brings danger: soul-sucking Dementors hover over the school, an ally of the accursed
He-Who-Cannot-Be-Named lurks within the castle walls, and fearsome wizard Sirius Black escapes Azkaban.
And Harry will confront them all.
Harry Potter, played by Daniel Radcliffe.
Ron Weasley, played by Rupert Grint.
Hermione Granger, played by Emma Watson.
Rubeus Hagrid, played by Robbie Coltrane.
Albus Dumbledore, played by Michael Gambon.
Sirius Black, played by Gary Oldman.
Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban is a 2004 fantasy film
directed by Alfonso Cuarón from a screenplay by Steve Kloves.
It is based on the 1999 novel Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban by J.
It is the sequel to Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets (2002) and
the third instalment in the Harry Potter film series.
The film stars Daniel Radcliffe as Harry Potter, alongside Rupert Grint and Emma Watson
as Harry's best friends Ron Weasley and Hermione Granger, respectively.
It chronicles Harry's third year at Hogwarts and his quest to uncover the truth about his past, including the
connection recently escaped Azkaban prisoner Sirius Black has to Harry and his deceased parents.
With this film, the Harry Potter series switched to a
longer eighteen-month production cycle.
Cuarón was selected as director from a list that
included Callie Khouri and Kenneth Branagh.
The cast of previous instalments returned for the film, with the additions of Gary
Oldman, David Thewlis, Timothy Spall, and Emma Thompson, among others.
It was the first appearance of Michael Gambon as Professor Albus
Dumbledore, due to Richard Harris's death in 2002.
Principal photography began in February 2003 at Leavesden Film Studios.
It was the first in the series to extensively use real-life locations,
with sets built in Scotland and scenes shot in London.
Filming wrapped in November 2003.
The film was released on 31 May 2004 in the United
Kingdom, and on 4 June 2004 in North America.
It was the first Harry Potter film to use IMAX
Technology and was released in IMAX theaters.
Prisoner of Azkaban grossed a total of $808 million worldwide, making it
the second-highest-grossing film of 2004, behind Shrek 2.
The film received critical acclaim, with particular praise for
Cuarón's direction and the lead actors' performances.
It is credited for marking a notable shift in the franchise's tone and directing style and
is often regarded by critics and fans alike as the best Harry Potter film.
It was nominated for two Academy Awards, Best Original Music Score and
Best Visual Effects, at the 77th Academy Awards in 2004.
It was followed by Harry Potter and the Goblet of Fire in 2005.
The film explores themes of witch, school friend, friendship, flying, magic.
The tone is lighthearted.